Aaron T. Wood

6059 Carrollton Ave, Indianapolis, IN 46220 woodadvantage@gmail.com ~ 917.445.6990

Business professional with excellent data analysis skills and experience with operational process improvement. Certified General Appraiser with 16 years of commercial real estate valuation experience including financial analysis and the application of discounted cash flow concepts. Strong verbal and written communication skills. Expert in Excel and Word, beginner in C#/.NET, MySQL, Swift, and Python.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Wood Advantage – Licensed in Indiana and Illinois

May 2012 - Current

- ➤ Became MAI in 2017.
- Numerous online coursework in software development and data analytics.

Metropolitan Valuation Services – New York, NY Commercial Appraiser

October 2011 – May 2012

Performed valuation analysis of commercial office, multi-family residential, retail, industrial and mixed-use properties for bank and private clients.

Key Achievements:

- > Simultaneous organization of multiple assignment types and deadlines
- Performed market analysis and tax comparability analysis

Appraisers and Planners, Inc. – New York, NY Commercial Appraiser

February 2008 – October 2011

Performed estate valuation and portfolio appraisals for commercial office, multi-family residential, retail, industrial and mixed-use properties.

Key Achievements:

- > Evaluated property in excess of \$40 million
- > Trained and mentored junior appraisers
- > Completed all advanced coursework for MAI certification, submitted a 3,000 hour MAI experience log

Correll Commercial Real Estate – Indianapolis, IN Commercial Appraiser 2003-2007

October 2003 – December 2007

Appraised industrial, retail, multi-family, office and special purpose properties for bank and private clients. Persistent process improvement of report creation, initiated a fully digital report process from start to finish.

Key Achievements:

- ➤ Valued property in excess of \$3 million
- ➤ Instigated multiple software and hardware transitions
- Created redundant backup and recovery systems
- > Completed all coursework and experience hours for CG certification

Real Estate Salesperson 2005-2007

Brokerage of multi-family and manufactured housing properties.

Key Achievements:

- Co-created a brokerage business in multi-family and manufactured housing
- > Grew a database of brokerage contacts, developed with a proprietary method
- Created email campaigns and brokerage brochures for listings

EDUCATION

B.S. Agricultural Economics, 2003 • Purdue University

Appraisal Institute coursework toward MAI designation and assorted CE seminars and lectures